var quiz = [{
  "question": "Assuming Pluto is not a planet, how many known planets are there in our solar system?",
  "choices": [
    "6",
    "7",
    "8",
    "9"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "8",
  "answerBlurb": "There are 8 known planets in our solar system."
},

{
  "question": "How far is our moon from the Earth?",
  "choices": [
    "282,400 km",
    "384,400 km",
    "157,600 km",
    "502,600 km"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "384,400 km",
  "answerBlurb": "The moon is 384,400 km from the Earth."
},

{
  "question": "How far is the Earth from the Sun?",
  "choices": [
   "56-59 million km",
   "87-91 million km",
   "120-124 million km",
   "147-152 million km"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "147-152 million km",
  "answerBlurb": "The Earth's orbit is elliptical, meaning it can be anywhere between 147 million and 152 million km away from the Sun at any given time."
},

{
  "question": "What does AU stand for?",
  "choices": [
   "Astronomical Unit",
   "Astral Unit",
   "Astronomical Unity",
   "Astral Unity"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Astronomical Unit",
  "answerBlurb": "AU stands for Astronomical Unit, or the average distance between the Earth and the Sun."
},

{
  "question": "Which planet in our solar system reaches the highest surface temperature?",
  "choices": [
   "Mercury",
   "Venus",
   "Mars",
   "Jupiter"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Venus",
  "answerBlurb": "Venus has a surface temperature of 462 degrees celcius, higher than Mercury's at 430 degrees celcius. This is due to Venus' thick atmosphere which retains heat."
},

{
  "question": "Which planet is the largest in our solar system?",
  "choices": [
   "Earth",
   "Uranus",
   "Neptune",
   "Jupiter"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Jupiter",
  "answerBlurb": "Jupiter is the largest planet in the solar system, having a mass that is 2.5 times larger than every other planet's mass combined!"
},

{
  "question": "Which planet is the smallest in our solar system?",
  "choices": [
   "Mercury",
   "Earth",
   "Neptune",
   "Mars"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Mercury",
  "answerBlurb": "Mercury is the smallest planet in the solar system, having a diameter only 1.4 times larger than our Moon."
},

{
  "question": "How many known moons does Jupiter have?",
  "choices": [
   "42",
   "54",
   "67",
   "74"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "67",
  "answerBlurb": "Jupiter has 67 moons, the highest number out of all of the planets in our solar system."
},

{
  "question": "Pluto is a:-",
  "choices": [
   "Dwarf planet",
   "Asteroid",
   "Meteor",
   "Planet"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Dwarf planet",
  "answerBlurb": "Pluto was recently reclassified as a dwarf planet rather than a planet."
},

{
  "question": "In which year did humans first walk on the Moon?",
  "choices": [
   "1961",
   "1963",
   "1957",
   "1969"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "1969",
  "answerBlurb": "The first mission to land on the moon was successfully launched in 1969 by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)."
},

{
  "question": "In which year did humans first travel into space?",
  "choices": [
   "1961",
   "1963",
   "1957",
   "1969"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "1961",
  "answerBlurb": "In 1961, the Soviet Union launched the first human being into space."
},

{
  "question": "In which year was the first satellite sent into space?",
  "choices": [
   "1961",
   "1963",
   "1957",
   "1969"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "1957",
  "answerBlurb": "The Soviet Union launched the first satellite into space in 1957."
},

{
  "question": "How long does it take for the Internation Space Station (ISS) to complete one orbit of the Earth?",
  "choices": [
   "40 minutes",
   "90 minutes",
   "3 hours",
   "14 hours"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "90 minutes",
  "answerBlurb": "It takes the ISS just 90 minutes to travel around the Earth, travelling at 7.66 km/s. That's more than 15 orbits per day!"
},

{
  "question": "Approximately how long does it take for the Moon to complete one orbit of the Earth?",
  "choices": [
   "27 days",
   "13 days",
   "5 days",
   "1 day"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "27 days",
  "answerBlurb": "It takes the moon 27 days to travel around the Earth. The moon travels 2cm further away from the Earth every year."
},

{
  "question": "In which year was the first Space Shuttle launched?",
  "choices": [
   "1977",
   "1981",
   "1986",
   "1990"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "1981",
  "answerBlurb": "The first Space Shuttle launch took place in 1981."
},

{
  "question": "In which year was the Voyager 1 spacecraft launched?",
  "choices": [
   "1977",
   "1981",
   "1986",
   "1990"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "1977",
  "answerBlurb": "Voyager 1 was launched in 1977, its original mission to collect data about Jupiter and Saturn. As of 2012, it has made the historic journey into interstellar space, and is currently much farther away from the Sun than Pluto!"
},

{
  "question": "Who was the first human to walk on the Moon?",
  "choices": [
   "Neil A. Armstrong",
   "Michael Collins",
   "Edwin 'Buzz' Aldrin",
   "Yuri Gagarin"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Neil A. Armstrong",
  "answerBlurb": "Neil Armstrong was the first man to walk on the Moon."
},

{
  "question": "Who was the first human to travel into space?",
  "choices": [
   "Neil A. Armstrong",
   "Michael Collins",
   "Edwin 'Buzz' Aldrin",
   "Yuri Gagarin"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Yuri Gagarin",
  "answerBlurb": "The Soviet Union sent the first human into space, Yuri Gagarin. He returned after completing one orbit of Earth."
},

{
  "question": "What is the surface temperature of the Sun (in degrees Celcius)?",
  "choices": [
   "4500",
   "5500",
   "6500",
   "7500"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "5500",
  "answerBlurb": "The Sun's surface temperature is 5500 degrees celcius, which is hot enough to vaporise every known material in the universe."
},

{
  "question": "What is the core temperature of the Sun (in degrees Celcius)?",
  "choices": [
   "3 million",
   "7 million",
   "10 million",
   "15 million"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "15 million",
  "answerBlurb": "The core temperature of the Sun is 15 million degrees Celcius. This energy is generated by the nuclear fusion of hydrogen atoms into helium atoms."
},

{
  "question": "What type of star is our Sun?",
  "choices": [
   "Yellow dwarf",
   "Red giant",
   "White dwarf",
   "Neutron star"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "Yellow dwarf",
  "answerBlurb": "Our Sun is a yellow dwarf, one of the more common types of star."
},

{
  "question": "What is the speed of light in a vacuum?",
  "choices": [
   "200,000 km/s",
   "250,000 km/s",
   "300,000 km/s",
   "350,000 km/s"
  ],
  "correctAnswer": "300,000 km/s",
  "answerBlurb": "Light travels at approximately 300,000 km/s in a vacuum, however its speed varies depending on the medium it travels through. For instance, its speed through water is around 225,000 km/s."
}]


